Guide to Connor and Neff blues collection
Oral History of American Music
Connor and Neff Blues Interviews
1964 1976
BL
Oral History of American Music
35 Audiotape Reels
67 Audiocassettes
123 Computer Files
48.5 gigabytes
Connor, Anthony, 1946-
Neff, Robert, 1930-
Scope and Contents
The Connor and Neff Blues Collection consists of 96 interviews with various blues musicians and blues industry figures. These interviews were the basis for the 1975 book The Blues by Anthony Connor and Robert Neff.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. To request access to recordings or transcripts of interviews (if available), see OHAM's website.
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online.
Blues Musicians; Women blues musicians; African American musicians; Blues (Music)
- Allison, Luther
  - Allison, Luther, 1976 October 26; BL 64; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327103)
    Allison, Luther, 1939-1997
- Bell, Carey
  - Bell, Carey, 1974 May 7; BL 42; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326923)
    Bell, Carey, 1936-2007
- Below, Fred
  - Below, Fred, unknown; BL 8; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326345)
    Below, Fred, 1926-1988
  - Below, Fred, 1973; BL 7; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item 39002038326337)
- Benton, Buster
  - Benton, Buster, 1974 May 11; BL 43; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326931)
    Scope and Contents
    Tape also contains live footage of Willie Dixon's band.
    Benton, Buster, 1932-1996
- Bishop, Elvin
  - Bishop, Elvin, 1974 August 13; BL 61; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327145)
    Bishop, Elvin (1942-10-21-)
- Brooks, Lonnie
  - Brooks, Lonnie, 1974 July 23; BL 52; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327020)
    Brooks, Lonnie (1933-12-18-2017-04-01)
- Brown, Clarence "Gatemouth"
  - Brown, Clarence "Gatemouth", 1973 June 29; BL 19; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326444)
    Brown, Clarence, 1924-2005
- Cotton, James
  - Cotton, James, unknown; BL 1; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326535, Item barcode 39002038326527, Item barcode 39002038326519, Item barcode 39002038326501)
    Cotton, James, 1935-2017
- Dawkins, Jimmy
  - Dawkins, Jimmy, unknown; BL 11; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326378)
    Dawkins, Jimmy (19361024-20130410)
  - Dawkins, Jimmy, 1973 June; BL 12; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326386)
- Diddley, Bo
  - Diddley, Bo, 1974 April 3; BL 37-38; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326873, Item barcode 39002038326881)
    Bo Diddley, 1928-2008
- Dixon, Willie
  - Dixon, Willie, unknown; BL 6; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326469)
    Dixon, Willie, 1915-1992
  - Dixon, Willie, 1973; BL 7; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326337)
  - Dixon, Willie, 1974 July 26; BL 56; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327186)
- Guy, Phil
  - Guy, Phil, 1974 July 2; BL 47; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326972)
    Guy, Phil (1940-04-28-2008-08-20)
- Guy, Buddy
  - Guy, Buddy, undated; BL 49; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326998)
    Guy, Buddy (19360730)
- Harvey, Ted
  - Harvey, Ted, 1973 July 25; BL 21-22; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 2 Audiotape Reels (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326550, Item barcode 39002038326568)
- Hooker, John Lee
  - Hooker, John Lee, 1973 September; BL 29-30; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 2 Audiotape Reels (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326824, Item barcode 39002038326832)
    Hooker, John Lee (1917-08-22?-2001-06-21-)
  - Hooker, John Lee, 1974 March 10; BL 36; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326865)
- Hutto, Joseph Benjamin "J.B."
  - Hutto, Joseph Benjamin "J.B.", 1973 June 26; BL 12-13; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326386, Item barcode 39002038326394)
    Hutto, J. B. (1926-04-29-1983-06-12)
- Johnson, Kennard
  - Johnson, Kennard "Kenny the Snake", unknown; BL 2; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326519)
    Johnson, Kennard
- Johnson, Luther "Georgia Boy"
  - Johnson, Luther "Georgia Boy", undated; BL 36; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326865)
    Johnson, Luther, 1934-1976
- King, Freddy
  - King, Freddy, 1973 October 3; BL 28; King, Freddy, 1934-1976; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326816)
  - King, Freddie, 1974 August 2; BL60; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327152)
    King, Freddy, 1934-1976
- Koester, Bob
  - Koester, Bob, 1973 June 27; BL 17; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326436)
    Koester, Bob, 1932-
- Koester, David
  - Koester, David, 1973 June 27; BL 16; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326428)
    Koester, David
- Lawhorn, Sammy
  - Lawhorn, Sammy, undated; BL 57; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327178)
    Lawhorn, Sammy (19350712-19900429)
- Littlejohn, John
  - Littlejohn, John, 1974 July 26; BL 55-56; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327194, Item barcode 39002038327186)
    Littlejohn, Johnny, 1931-1994
- Luandrew, Albert ("Sunnyland Slim")
  - Luandrew, Albert ("Sunnyland Slim"), 1973 June 27; BL 18; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326451)
    Sunnyland Slim, 1907-1995
- McGhee, Brownie
  - McGhee, Brownie, ca. 1974 July; BL 44; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326949)
    McGhee, Brownie, 1915-1996
- McGhee, Brownie and Sonny Terry
  - McGhee, Brownie and Sonny Terry, 1974 June 26; BL 45; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326956)
    with Sonny Terry
    McGhee, Brownie, 1915-1996; Terry, Sonny (1911-10-24-1986-03-11)
- Montgomery, Eurrel Wilford "Little Brother"
  - Montgomery, Eurreal Wilford "Little Brother", 1973 June 26; BL 13-14; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 2 Audiotape Reels (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326394, Item barcode 39002038326402)
    Montgomery, Little Brother, 1906-1985
- Murphy, Matt
  - Murphy, Matt "Guitar", 1974 March 10; BL 35; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326857)
    Murphy, Matt, (Guitarist) (1929-12-28-2018-06-15)
- Myers, Louis
  - Myers, Louis, undated; BL 10; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326360)
    Myers, Louis (1929-09-18-1994-09-05)
  - Myers, Louis, undated; BL 11; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326378)
- Myers, Dave
  - Myers, Dave, 1974 July 26; BL 58; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327160)
    Myers, Dave, 1926-2001
- Parker, Dan
  - Parker, Dan, undated; BL 4; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326329)
  - Parker, Dan, undated; BL 5; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326485)
- Phillips, Esther
  - Phillips, Esther, undated; BL 61 x; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327137)
    Phillips, Esther, 1935-1984
  - Phillips, Esther, 1974 October 21; BL 62; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327129)
  - Phillips, Esther, undated; BL 63; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327111)
- Rebenneck, Malcolm John ("Dr, John")
  - Rebenneck, Malcolm John ("Dr. John"), undated; BL 65-66; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327095, Item barcode 39002038327087)
    Dr. John, 1941-2019
- Reidy, Bob
  - Reidy, Bob, 1974 July 24; BL 54; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327202)
    Riedy, Bob
- Seals, Frank "Son"
  - Seals, Frank "Son", 1974 July 24; BL 53; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327038)
    Seals, Son (1942-08-13-2004-12-20)
- Sharif, Little Beau
  - Sharif, Little Beau, 1974 March 10; BL 35; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326857)
    Sharif, LIttle Beau
- Shaw, Eddie and Emery "Detroit Junior" Williams, Jr.
  - Shaw, Eddie and Emery "Detroit Junior" Williams, Jr., 1973 October 26; BL 31; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326840)
    Shaw, Eddie, 1937-2018; Detroit Junior, 1931-2005
- Shines, Johnny
  - Shines, Johnny, 1974 June 30; BL 46; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326964)
    Shines, Johnny (1915-04-26-1992-04-20)
- Smith, George "Harmonica"
  - Smith, George "Harmonica", undated; BL 3; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326311)
    Smith, George, 1924-1983
  - Smith, George "Harmonica", undated; BL 4; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326329)
  - Smith, George "Harmonica", and his band, undated; BL 5; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326485)
- Smith, Willie "Big Eyes"
  - Smith, Willie "Big Eyes", 1973 August 10; BL 26; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326790)
    Smith, Willie, 1936-2011
- Sykes, Roosevelt
  - Sykes, Roosevelt, 1974 October 21; BL 62; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327129)
    Sykes, Roosevelt (1906-01-31-1983-07-11)
- Taylor, Theodore Roosevelt "Hound Dog"
  - Taylor, Theodore Roosevelt "Hound Dog", undated; BL 8; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326345)
    Taylor, Hound Dog, 1915-1975
  - Taylor, Theodore Roosevelt "Hound Dog", undated; BL 9; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326352)
  - Taylore, Theodor Roosevelt "Hound Dog", undated; BL 10; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326360)
  - Taylor, Theodore Roosevelt "Hound Dog", undated; BL 21; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326550)
  - Taylor, Theodore Roosevelt "Hound Dog", undated; BL 22; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326568)
- Taylor, Koko
  - Taylor, Koko, 1974 July 23; BL 52; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327020)
    Taylor, Koko (1928-09-28-2009-06-03)
  - Taylor, Koko, 1974 July 30; BL 59; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038327160)
- Thornton, Willie Mae "Big Mama"
  - Thornton, Willie Mae "Big Mama", 1974 February 10; BL 33 a-b; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 23 pp.
    Thornton, Big Mama (1926-12-11-1984-07-25)
- Tucker, Luther
  - Tucker, Luther, 1973 September; BL 29; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326824)
    Tucker, Luther (1936-01-20-1993-06-18)
- Vinson, Eddie "Cleanhead"
  - Vinson, Eddie "Cleanhead", 1973 June 30; BL 19; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326444)
    Vinson, Eddie (1917-12-18-1988-07-02)
  - Vinson, Eddie "Cleanhead", 1973 July 25; BL 20; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326543)
- Wallace, Sippie
  - Wallace, Sippie, 1974 October 21; BL 62; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item 39002038327129)
    Wallace, Sippie (18981101-19861101)
- Waterman, Dick
  - Waterman, Dick, 1973 July 28; BL 23; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326576)
    Waterman, Dick
  - Waterman, Dick, 1973 July 28; BL 24; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326584)
- Waters, Muddy
  - Waters, Muddy, 1973 July 9; BL 25 a-b; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326782)
    Muddy Waters, 1915-1983
  - Waters, Muddy, 1973 August 9; BL 26; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326790)
    Band members, Calvin "Fuzz" Jones, Hollywood Fats, and Mojo Buford, are also present.
  - Waters, Muddy, 1973 August 10; BL 27; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326808)
- Wells, Junior
  - Wells, Junior, 1974 July 5; BL 48; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326980)
    Wells, Junior, 1934-1998
  - Wells, Junior, 1974 July 5; BL 49; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326998)
- Young, "Mighty" Joe
  - Young, "Mighty" Joe, 1974 April 6; BL 39; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326899)
    Young, Mighty Joe
  - Young, "Mighty" Joe, 1974 April 6; BL 40; Connor, Anthony, 1946-; Neff, Robert, 1930-; 1 Audiotape Reel (Box 39002038324142, Item barcode 39002038326907)